The Saga Concludes.
Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker is a adventure, action,
science fiction film directed by J.J. Abrams.
The surviving Resistance faces the First Order once again as the
journey of Rey, Finn and Poe Dameron continues.
With the power and knowledge of generations
behind them, the final battle begins.
General Leia Organa, played by Carrie Fisher.
Luke Skywalker, played by Mark Hamill.
Rey, played by Daisy Ridley.
Kylo Ren / Ben Solo, played by Adam Driver.
Finn, played by John Boyega.
Poe Dameron, played by Oscar Isaac.
Star Wars: The Rise of Skywalker (also known as Star Wars: Episode IX – The Rise of Skywalker) is
a 2019 American epic space opera film produced, co-written, and directed by J.
Produced by Lucasfilm and Bad Robot, and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the third installment of the Star Wars sequel
trilogy, following The Force Awakens (2015) and The Last Jedi (2017), and the final episode of the nine-part "Skywalker saga".
Its cast includes Carrie Fisher, Mark Hamill, Adam Driver, Daisy Ridley, John Boyega,
Oscar Isaac, Anthony Daniels, Naomi Ackie, Domhnall Gleeson, Richard E.
Grant, Lupita Nyong'o, Keri Russell, Joonas Suotamo, Kelly
Marie Tran, Ian McDiarmid, and Billy Dee Williams.
The film follows Rey, Finn, and Poe Dameron as they lead the remnants of the Resistance in a final stand against Supreme Leader Kylo
Ren and the First Order, who are now allied by the resurrected Sith Lord, Emperor Palpatine, Rey's paternal grandfather.
Following initial reports that The Last Jedi director Rian Johnson would write the script for Episode IX, in August 2015, Colin Trevorrow was hired to
direct and to write a script with his collaborator Derek Connolly; both ultimately retain story credit with Abrams and Chris Terrio.
In September 2017, Trevorrow left the project following creative differences
with producer Kathleen Kennedy, and Abrams returned as director.
John Williams, composer for the previous episodic films, returned to
compose the score, making it his final score for the franchise.
Principal photography began in August 2018 at Pinewood Studios in England and wrapped
in February 2019, with post-production completed in November 2019.
With a net budget of approximately $489.9 million, it
is the most expensive film ever made.
The Rise of Skywalker premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on December 16,
2019, and was released in the United States on December 20.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $1.077 billion, making it the
seventh-highest-grossing film of 2019, but also the lowest-grossing of the sequel trilogy.
It received three nominations at the 92nd Academy Awards (Best Original Score, Best Visual Effects, and Best Sound Editing) as well as
three at the 73rd British Academy Film Awards (also Best Special Visual Effects, Best Original Music, and Best Sound).
It won five awards at the 46th Saturn Awards,
including Best Science Fiction Film.
The tone is thought_provoking.